[Music]
Hey, hey, and welcome back to Living in
Central Texas. If you've been
considering trading in city traffic for
small town charm, spacious living, and a
Texas sized value, then stick with me as
we explore Troy, Texas, a hidden little
gem just 10 minutes north of Templeton.
[Music]
Don't forget to like this video,
subscribe, and click the bell
notification so that you can stay up to
date on all things real estate here in
Central Texas. Okay, so today we're
going to be checking out three wonderful
new construction opportunities here in
the Troy, Texas area. There are also
fantastic land options. So, if you've
been considering, you know, maybe buying
your own little piece of land to build
on in the future, um low taxes, um just
whatever your heart's desire, this is a
really great spot to do that in. But
today, we'll be exploring those three
new construction opportunities,
including this beautiful Kurther's new
build behind me. They are building a ton
in this neighborhood. It's um we're in
Turtle Creek. It's a master planned
community here in the area.
There are also some other really great
builders here. Um, but we'll do this
first and then we're going to check out
some really affordable town homes by
Flint Rocks. Probably the most
affordable options for living in this
area. And then our last stop is going to
be a Jarlic new construction home, which
was their parade of homes this year. I
saw it just a few months ago when I was
random randomly showing some clients. It
was absolutely stunning and it has a
pool. It's just really great. So, we're
going to check out all three of these. I
think you're going to love them. And
we're also going to discuss what it's
like to live here, including shopping,
schools, so much more. It's going to be
a really great video. Let's get started.
First stop is the Turtle Creek Community
in Troy, Texas. This particular builder
is known for their quality
craftsmanship, smart layouts, and
upscale finishes, all without breaking
the budget. Whether you're growing a
family or looking for some peace and
space, these homes offer generous square
footage, open concept living, and
beautiful curb appeal. The front is a
mix of stone and brick. And the lot
sizes are really great for this price
point, ranging from 3 369,000
to the low or mid400s.
And of course, these builders at this
moment are offering some really
fantastic incentives. You can really see
the craftsmanship, including crown
molding throughout main living spaces,
upgraded light fixtures, ceramic
woodlike tile, and just overall
attention to detail. In this home,
there's the woodlike tile in the main
living spaces and carpet in the
bedrooms.
The kitchen has stunning honey oak
cabinets and oversized center island.
Stunning pendants and a super modern
backsplash. I love how this kitchen
overlooks the main living space, which
features the wood burning fireplace and
cathedral ceilings.
This entire space feels super elegant.
The primary bedroom is generously sized
with recess lighting, and the primary
bathroom has a large soaking tub,
walk-in shower, and dual vanities. Don't
forget the large closet.
[Music]
The backyard features a small covered
patio, full saw and irrigation, and a
full exterior privacy fence.
Our
next stop is a beautiful luxury new
construction home in the established
River Oaks Estates community. This was
built by Jarlic Homes. He's a really
fabulous builder in the area. And this
property in particular was their parade
of homes this year. This property sits
on a spacious lot with a beautiful sense
of privacy while still being close to
everything Troy has to offer. If you're
looking for a home with character and
room to roam, this one deserves a closer
look. This is a four bed, two bath home
with about 2285 square ft. And the best
feature is hands down the oversized
nearly 3/4 of an acre lot with a
stunning inground pool. I thought the
lighting and abundance of windows was
fantastic. Um, and the beautiful views
no matter which room you're in. The
kitchen features two-toned painted
cabinets, quartz countertops, stainless
steel appliances, and an oversized
island. There is no carpet in this home,
just luxury vinyl plank throughout. This
home is on a septic system, not city
sewer, which is pretty common with
larger lots. The primary bathroom is
stunning with dual vanities, a large
soaking tub, walk-in shower, and
oversized closet. In general, the use of
space in this home was really fantastic.
This home in River Oaks is priced just
over 600,000. I think this gives a
really great comparison between luxury
living and more entry-level homes here
in the Troy area. Stop number three is
these College Park town homes. So, if
you're looking for lowmaintenance living
with a stylish touch, check out these
town homes in College Park. These are
ideal for first-time buyers, investors,
or anyone wanting move-in ready. Clean
lines, energy efficient features, and a
smart floor plan, all in a quiet
setting. I thought the backyards on
these were fantastic given the size and
price point of just over 200,000.
What a great entry home. This one in
particular was the model home that I'm
touring, but most of these floor plans
offer about offer three bed, two
bathrooms, and over,00 square ft of
thoughtfully designed living space.
While this home has vinyl plank being
the model, most of their town homes
feature loan lowmaintenance sand and
seal concrete flooring throughout. A
fully solded yard with a privacy fence
and irrigation system, and a modern
kitchen equipped with stainless steel
appliances, microwave, stove, and
dishwasher.
Ceiling fans in both the master suite
and family room are standard, providing
an added comfort year round.
[Music]
Now we're transitioning to the schools.
Troy ISD is a big draw for families. The
district consistently scores well on
academic performance and the community
takes pride in supporting the Trojans.
From Friday night footballs to band and
FFA events, schools here include Troy
Elementary,
middle and high school. All known for
smaller class sizes and strong student
teacher relationships, food and local
favorites. In this town, you have
Halisco's Mexican restaurant and Ernie's
Fried Chicken. Troy gives you the space
and quiet, but you're still really close
to everything. for day-to-day errands or
just a quick trip out. Temple is just 10
minutes south with an abundance of
restaurants including BJ's, Olive
Garden, Bird Creek Burgers, Picnettis,
and so many awesome options. I could go
on and on, but Temple also has really
great shopping options, including
Target, Walmart, um HB, the Temple Mall,
and of course, you have the full Scott
and White medical system in Temple. So,
if you'd like to know more about Temple,
Texas, head on over to my map tour of
Temple.
Belton is nearby, too, with historic
downtown charm, breweries, and lakeside
activities. And if you need a bigger
city trip, Austin is just an hour away
south of Troy, and Waco is about 30
minutes north. So, why relocate here?
Well, people move to Troy for the
lifestyle, more home for your dollar,
and a tight-knit community, and room to
grow. Not to mention, the property taxes
are much lower here than some other
areas. One of the best features is that
you can get those low property taxes
more bang for your buck while still
being 10 minutes out from larger areas
like Temple and Belton.
Whether you're escaping the hustle or
planning roots for your family, it's
just kind of a place where neighbors
wave, kids ride bikes after dinner, and
life slows down just enough. Hey, thanks
so much for touring Troy, Texas with me
today. I hope you found it helpful. If
you're not quite ready to reach out, you
can head on over to livingx.com
where we have some really fabulous
resources including an interactive map
so you can see all the neighboring
areas, market stats, um other home
tours, homes for sale. It's just a
really great resource all around.
There's also a free relocation guide for
you to download if that is helpful for
you. And I appreciate you taking the
time to watch this. Until next time,
I'll see you on the next one.